Okay, so in this video then, we are going
to discuss the scope management plan.
Okay.
Now, just as a quick review,
remember in one of the
earlier videos we talked about
the project management plan.
And the project management plan is made up
of many, many components, right?
It's made up of the subsidiary plans,
the subsidiary management plans,
is made up of the baselines, right?
And mainly the scope
schedule cost baselines,
and then there's some
additional components.
And collectively, all of these documents
make up the project management plan.
Now, one of the
components then of the project
management plan are the
subsidiary management plans.
And all of the knowledge areas contains a
subsidiary management plan.
And a subsidiary management plan has a
word management plan in the title.
So in this case then, since we're talking
about scope management, right,
then scope management plan is one of the
subsidiary plans, right?
One of the two subsidiary plans.
The other one is
requirements management plan,
which I'll talk about in a separate video.
However, remember any of these management
plans, any of these subsidiary plans,
they are documenting procedures.
They are documenting how, how we are going
to plan.
manage, execute any aspect of the project,
right?
How we're going to plan, manage,
execute this particular knowledge area?
Is documenting procedures?
So the scope management plan then is
documenting that just that.
It's documenting procedures.
Is documenting how the scope is going to
be defined?
It's going to be documenting procedures
for preparing the scope statement.
The scope management plan does not contain
the scope.
It's not telling you what the scope of the
project is.
That's a scope statement, again,
which we'll cover in a separate video.
But the scope management
plan is documenting,
how are we going to
develop the scope statement?
How are we going to come up with the scope
of the project?
What's our procedure?
Remember, progressive elaboration.
You start off with a high-level concept,
you drill down into the details.
Well, in this case as well, you're
starting off with a high-level scope,
and then you're drilling down into the
details, right?
Well, how are we going to do that?
What level of detail, right?
All procedures are going to be documented
here in the scope management plan.
So how the scope will be defined,
developed, controlled, how procedures or
what the procedures are going to be for
preparing the scope statement.
We're going to be talking about the work
breakdown structure in a separate video,
how we're going to create the work
breakdown structure.
So what are the procedures for us?
approving the scope
management plan, what are
the procedures for
baselining the scope, right?
One of the baselines is a scope baseline.
What are the procedures for that?
What happens if halfway through the
project we realize that we've missed a
major scope of the project or the scope
needs to be updated?
How do we handle that situation?
How do we handle a situation where halfway
through the project, senior management
decides to increase the scope,
the project.
How do we handle that situation?
Right.
So the process for managing scope changes,
documenting procedures for scopes changes,
right?
How are we going to do that?
So that's all documented here in the scope
management plan.
I said scope management plan does not
contain the actual scope itself.
It's documenting procedures, just like all
management plans, right?
They're all, all documenting procedures.
So if you understand that, you don't
necessarily need to sit down and think
about all the different possibilities that
a scope management plan or requirements
management plan or a cost management plan
might be documenting.
There's many, many items
going to be documenting,
but the main thing is they
are all called procedures.
They're all documenting procedures.
They're all documenting the how for any of
these management plans.
Okay.
Now, along with this some of the common
tools right that I use are some of the
common tools that you can use to develop
this scope so some of the key tools and
techniques right expert judgment your own
knowledge and experience and plus
knowledge and experience of others around
you right so you know how to create the
scope of the project you know what's
involved you've done this before then
you're gonna utilize their own knowledge
and experience but let's say you don't
know let's say you haven't
done this before Well,
you're going to utilize
subject matter experts.
You're going to reach out to team leads
and other knowledgeable people, right?
Other subject matter experts.
So anybody can give you expert judgment.
Now, another important one is this one
called alternatives analysis.
An alternative analysis is literally as it
sounds.
What alternatives are
there to meeting the same
goal, right, or for
accomplishing the same goal?
So, I mean, literally the definition,
identifying different ways of meeting the
scope, determining the
best approach or strategy,
in this case, to conduct
the scope process.
But we see alternatives analysis over and
over again.
And like I said, it is literally as it
sounds.
So, for example, we're building a road and
there's a river.
Well, do we build a tunnel or do we build
a bridge?
Those are two alternatives.
We need to get to the other side.
So should we have a tunnel or should we
build a bridge?
Right, two alternatives.
Or should we, there's
another bridge further down,
you know, further down
river or further up river.
But maybe we could divert the road up to
the other bridge.
Right, these are different alternatives.
Right, so alternatives analysis is
literally, literally as it sounds.
What alternatives are there.
So this is another key tool and technique.
Right, we see this over and over again for
many, many, processes.
And in this case, we're talking about
scope.
And then meetings.
We're going to have many, many meetings.
So this is another common tool and technique
that we'll see over and over again.
We need to discuss.
We need to identify.
We need to come to a decision.
We may have a meeting.
So anyway, just remember for this section
then, the main takeaway for this section
is that the scope management plan is
documenting procedures.
Procedures for developing the scope.
Procedure for developing the work
breakdown structure, procedures for
determining how detailed the scope
statement is going to be.
It doesn't actually contain the scope
itself.